Aakash Vinod Chaurasia

1255 E University Drive Road, Block No R, Apt no- 3025, Tempe, Arizona achauras@asu.edu | 1-4807383458|Linkedin| GitHub | Website

OBJECTIVES

Currently working as Junior Java developer in Nextiva. PLSQL developer with 2 years of experience in Accenture Services Pvt. Ltd. 3 years' experience in android development and java. Seeking a full time software engineer position for summer 17

EDUCATION

- Masters in Computer Science, Arizona State University GPA 3.72 May 2017
- Bachelors of Engineering in Information Technology, KJ Somaiya College Of Engg 68.6% June 2013

TECHNOLOGY/LANGUAGES

- JAVA, SPRING, HIBERNATE, ANDROID, SQL, PLSQL, SQLlite, REST Services, Python, C++, C#, Git, PHP, MACROS, VbScript, Unix, TCP/IP, UDP, VBA, JSON, MATLAB, JavaScript, CSS, HTML 5, ASP, JSP, SERVLET, XML
- INTELLIJ, Visual Studio, Android Studio, Net Beans, GitLab, SVN, QC, Rally, Excel, Putty, Google APIS, MS ACCESS, Eclipse, AdMob.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nextiva Inc – Junior Software Developer – June 2016 to present

- Developed 26/85 Restful web Services for Nextiva VoiceService in order to build a SOA product.
- Worked on Spring Framework for creating the MVC architecture and RESTful services.
- For database access used Hibernate to fire SQL (Created 125 SQL queries) query from application to database.
- Created functional test cases using Junit for testing the feature against different inputs with 85% coverage.
- Maintained version control, project management (Agile Development) using BitBucket, CA Rally tools respectively.
- Used Maven framework for deployment of web services on apache tomcat.

Accenture Services Pvt. Ltd. - Software Engineer - Nov 2013 to July 2015

- Migrated 100,000 records bi-weekly from Legacy system to Target SIEBEL, UIM, BRM, FMW
- Devised the workflow on BSS tool to run the ETL process which reduced time by 70%
- Retrieved xml files using SQL query for representing 100,000 records in single xml
- Designed 200 test Scripts for unit testing and performance testing.
- Built reports in tabular format for high end view to clients, which reduce manual work by 98%.
- Was Awarded the 'GO for GOLD' award for Problem Solving award in SEP 2014,commitment in Feb 2015

ACADEMIC & OTHER PROJECTS

Maven (Jan 2016 to current date)

- Implementing an android app city name as input, then displays list of restaurants in that city and clicking on list item, will navigate user to details page and runnable class for SplashActivity for 3 seconds.
- Added code for populating name of city depending on current location, Asynctask to fetch data from factual api.
- Created a custom listview using ArrayListAdapter and object concept, which contains details of restaurant.
 Used textView.onClickListener for address, website, phone to call intent of navigation, browser, dialer respectively.

Java Mini Database (Jan 2016 to May 2016)

- Implemented different page replacement policy for buffer pages which stores data. Ex LIFO, FIFIO, LRU-K, etc.
- Designed and created code for IE Join and IE Self Join, which performs faster than postgres and saves 60% of time.
- Built a code base for query estimation by taking samples, based on that generating a query plan which is efficient.

Estate Assistant (June 2012 to Apr 2013)

- Conceptualized a project for digitalization of buying and renting propertyIntegrated feature of navigation using raw maps for user to search properties, saved 80% of customer's time.
- Built a security feature of sending token for authentication, used BASE64 to upload image, which 40% time.

CERTIFICATION

HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers, <u>AMUNY977BT9E</u>. Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python), <u>SHZDU52EDXAM</u>. Python data Structure, <u>CFQRGGZ8P92C</u>. Python to access web API, <u>4VHEL89KUZP3</u>. Using Databases With Python, <u>J9T2TK88BTAB</u>.